<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Getting out of my comfort zone</title>
  <date>2026-06-29</date>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="video-embed">
      <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YmiJxWhIX8c" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </div>

    <p>Yeah, I was thinking about the previous video where I talked about getting out of my comfort zone. I figured I might as well talk about it right now because it perfectly connects with a lot of the things I value.</p>

    <p>When I was in quarantine, things got to the point where I had basically no friends. I literally went on Google and searched, "How do I make friends?" That sent me down a huge rabbit hole of videos and articles about making friends.</p>

    <p>At some point, I came across a YouTube video. It didn't have many views—I don't even know if it's still up—but it was this guy who made an entire exposure therapy plan.</p>

    <p>The first step was documenting how I felt. Then, every day, I would intentionally put myself into an uncomfortable social situation, like talking to someone new. Afterward, I would document how I felt again. There were other parts to it, too, but that was the main idea.</p>

    <p>Around that time, I had also moved to a new school. There were obviously other factors involved, but I was actually excited because it meant I had a fresh start. I didn't have to worry about people judging me based on who I used to be. No one knew me as "the quiet kid."</p>

    <p>I had a clean slate.</p>

    <p>My biggest goal was simply to make friends.</p>

    <p>Using that exposure therapy plan, my goal was to start one conversation—or even just join one conversation—every single day.</p>

    <p>It was honestly that bad. Back then, even joining a conversation felt difficult.</p>

    <p>So I pushed myself.</p>

    <p>At first, I might have only contributed a single sentence to a conversation, and that alone felt like a win.</p>

    <p>Little by little, though, I became more comfortable. Over time, it genuinely helped me become much more confident talking to people.</p>

    <p>I think I still have those journal entries somewhere. They documented exactly how I felt before and after each day.</p>

    <p>I even recorded myself while playing games like Rocket League or Genshin Impact. I'd just talk to myself, exactly like I'm doing now, and reflect on how the day went.</p>

    <p>I think I made it to around Day 30—maybe Day 32.</p>

    <p>After about a month, I finally felt like I didn't need those recordings anymore because I had found people I could actually talk to. I finally felt like I had friends.</p>

    <p>It was incredibly rewarding.</p>

    <p>Granted, that friend group didn't end up lasting. Four years later, things didn't really work out.</p>

    <p>But because of those friendships, I ended up meeting even more people.</p>

    <p>One of those friendships eventually led me to my current friend group through tennis.</p>

    <p>Then there were clubs, like the Beat Saber Club.</p>

    <p>Those people eventually became my day ones.</p>

    <p>They're real.</p>

    <p>Honestly, I'm incredibly grateful to have them.</p>

    <p>They're probably one of the biggest reasons why I'm so content with life now and why I don't really struggle with loneliness anymore.</p>

    <p>I can be my full, authentic self around them.</p>

    <p>It's great.</p>

    <p>So, if you're listening and you know who you are, thank you.</p>

    <p>Anyway, before I get into my friendship video, I wanted to talk about another situation where stepping outside my comfort zone completely changed my life.</p>

    <p>One of my biggest fears growing up was doing things alone.</p>

    <p>I always wanted someone to be with me whenever I went somewhere, especially social events or concerts.</p>

    <p>Even now, I notice people saying they won't go to a concert because they don't have anyone to go with.</p>

    <p>Nowadays, though, my mindset is different.</p>

    <p>If you really want to see an artist, just go by yourself.</p>

    <p>One experience completely changed how I looked at that.</p>

    <p>One day, Laufey posted an Instagram story showing where she was. I realized she was only about thirty minutes away from where I lived. She was near the venue where she was performing later that night.</p>

    <p>The concert itself was completely sold out.</p>

    <p>But she wasn't inside the venue yet.</p>

    <p>I remember thinking, "What if I just go?"</p>

    <p>So I drove over by myself and waited near the venue's back entrance.</p>

    <p>I honestly don't know what got into me that day, but I decided I was going to step outside my comfort zone.</p>

    <p>When I got there, there were already a few people waiting.</p>

    <p>I built up the courage to talk to them, and we all started chatting about Laufey.</p>

    <p>Then, sure enough, she walked by.</p>

    <p>I got to meet her, talk to her, and take a picture with her.</p>

    <p>For some reason, I never asked her to sign anything.</p>

    <p>Looking back, I definitely should have gotten an autograph too.</p>

    <p>But honestly, I was just happy that I got to meet her, especially considering how huge she is now.</p>

    <p>The crazy part happened afterward.</p>

    <p>A staff member came outside and told everyone waiting that if we stayed, there might be extra tickets available.</p>

    <p>So we waited.</p>

    <p>The concert had completely sold out, and resale tickets were going for around $400.</p>

    <p>Somehow, we ended up getting front-row balcony tickets for only $30.</p>

    <p>Those seats would've probably been worth close to $1,000 on resale.</p>

    <p>It was incredible.</p>

    <p>That was during her <em>Bewitched</em> tour, back when "From the Start" had just started blowing up but she was still performing at relatively small venues.</p>

    <p>Even better, I ended up making a bunch of new friends while waiting outside.</p>

    <p>Unfortunately, I don't really keep in touch with most of them anymore, but the fact that I was able to make friends there at all was amazing.</p>

    <p>That experience is another reason why I'm so much more comfortable doing things alone now.</p>

    <p>I became comfortable because I repeatedly exposed myself to uncomfortable situations.</p>

    <p>There's actually a psychology concept called the <strong>mere exposure effect</strong>.</p>

    <p>The more you're exposed to something, the more comfortable or familiar it starts to feel.</p>

    <p>From everything I've seen, that's also one of the best ways to overcome fear.</p>

    <p>You can correct me if I'm wrong, but from what I've learned, that's basically how you overcome most fears.</p>

    <p>You face them.</p>

    <p>That's why "face your fears" is such a common saying.</p>

    <p>It's really just repeated exposure.</p>

    <p>The fear might never disappear completely, but it becomes much smaller.</p>

    <p>I still have social anxiety sometimes.</p>

    <p>It's definitely not gone.</p>

    <p>But it's so much better than it used to be.</p>

    <p>And that's exactly why I value getting out of my comfort zone so highly.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
