<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>On Communication</title>
  <date>2026-07-23</date>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="video-embed">
      <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JGvKMPtyE8Q" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </div>

    <p>All right, this might sound a little crazy, but this is the fifth video I've recorded tonight, and it's almost 5:00 a.m. I really need to sleep because I have to wake up at 9:00 a.m.</p>

    <p>Hopefully this will be the last video. If I don't know what else to talk about, maybe I'll leave myself on a cliffhanger so I can keep making these videos and let you all know more about me.</p>

    <p>This video is about communication.</p>

    <p>Communication is another thing I highly value. It's something I never really thought much about before. I've mentioned that I've taken five college communication classes, originally just because I wanted to learn how to make friends. But communication is so much bigger than that. Whether it's in a work environment, relationships, friendships, or really any situation, communication is incredibly important.</p>

    <p>The story of why communication became such an important value for me actually started with Pokémon Club.</p>

    <p>My friends started the club, and we ended up getting an advisor who, years later, turned out to be a pedophile. That's a completely different story. But before all of that happened, he took the club way too seriously. Honestly, I did too, which probably wasn't a good thing.</p>

    <p>We planned meetings, submitted budgets, bought supplies, and organized events. Most of the time it was just arts and crafts or themed food, but we'd regularly have around fifty students show up. Fifty people in a small classroom gets pretty crowded, so every meeting felt like a pretty big event.</p>

    <p>Looking back, I definitely took it more seriously than I should have.</p>

    <p>Our advisor also ran clubs like Key Club, DECA, and FBLA. He basically advised all the "serious" clubs at the school. He was originally just a career counselor, but somehow he ended up advising a huge number of clubs.</p>

    <p>Obviously, he turned out to be a terrible person and was eventually arrested.</p>

    <p>As awful as he ended up being, I still learned something valuable from that experience.</p>

    <p>One of the biggest lessons I learned was the importance of communication.</p>

    <p>When I first joined the board, I was terrible at communicating.</p>

    <p>At the same time, I was also in a relationship that demanded almost all of my attention. Honestly, it went both ways because I still had an anxious attachment style. I was very clingy, and we basically devoted all of our attention to each other.</p>

    <p>Because of that, I neglected a lot of my other responsibilities.</p>

    <p>I wasn't communicating with anyone.</p>

    <p>For about six or seven months—from around September to February—I constantly received complaints that I wasn't communicating enough. At the time, I didn't understand what people meant or how I was supposed to fix it.</p>

    <p>Then, around February, something happened.</p>

    <p>I had an exam—or maybe it was a major assignment—that absolutely had to get done. It was due just a few hours before a Pokémon Club fundraiser.</p>

    <p>Instead of telling anyone ahead of time, I kept it to myself.</p>

    <p>I think I was just scared. My thought process was basically, "If I tell them I can't come, they'll be mad at me."</p>

    <p>That was before I realized that simply communicating usually solves the problem.</p>

    <p>Eventually, I worked up the courage, stepped outside my comfort zone, and told everyone, "Hey, I'm really sorry, but I have to finish this exam."</p>

    <p>I kept apologizing.</p>

    <p>Then our club advisor said something that's stuck with me ever since.</p>

    <p>Ironically, it was one of the only times he didn't get angry. He got mad over the smallest things in Pokémon Club, which is still funny to think about.</p>

    <p>But this time, he simply said,</p>

    <blockquote>"It's okay. As long as you communicate, that's all that matters."</blockquote>

    <p>That sentence has stayed with me ever since.</p>

    <p>Over the years, I've noticed that so many problems could have been avoided if people had just communicated.</p>

    <p>Whether it's me communicating or someone else communicating, it almost always comes down to simply telling people what's going on.</p>

    <p>It's funny that I learned such an important life lesson from Pokémon Club of all places.</p>

    <p>From that day on, I realized communication is essential—not just in clubs, but in work, relationships, friendships, planning, and honestly every part of life.</p>

    <p>There's also the public speaking side of communication, which I think is incredibly important.</p>

    <p>I started watching someone named Vin Jiang, and one thing he emphasizes is that your communication skills are just as important as your technical skills.</p>

    <p>His point is simple.</p>

    <p>You can be incredibly talented, but if nobody knows what you're capable of because you can't communicate it, then those skills become much less valuable.</p>

    <p>That idea really stuck with me.</p>

    <p>Between his content and all the communication classes I've taken, I realized how important it is to communicate clearly and confidently.</p>

    <p>I'm still not great at it.</p>

    <p>I'm still working on becoming better at talking to people.</p>

    <p>That's another reason communication is such a high priority for me.</p>

    <p>Even looking back at my previous relationship, communication became one of the biggest issues toward the end.</p>

    <p>Honestly, I don't think I communicated enough.</p>

    <p>So that's another lesson I've learned firsthand.</p>

    <p>This is actually an even shorter video than the last one, which is probably a good thing because I really need to sleep.</p>

    <p>Communication is just something I value very highly.</p>

    <p>I know I don't always show it—I can be terrible at replying to messages—but I genuinely believe communication is important.</p>

    <p>And honestly, I don't think I have much of an excuse.</p>

    <p>If I fail to communicate, that's on me.</p>

    <p>I'll apologize, and maybe I'll even make the same mistake again, but if someone holds me accountable, I'll own it.</p>

    <p>I really don't think there's much of an excuse for poor communication because if you have an excuse, you can usually communicate that excuse in the first place.</p>

    <p>I've noticed this during internships and in the workplace too.</p>

    <p>Communication is everything.</p>

    <p>If you're running late, let people know.</p>

    <p>If something comes up, let people know.</p>

    <p>It's usually that simple.</p>

    <p>Another thing I've noticed is that a huge number of conflicts come from simple miscommunication.</p>

    <p>That also ties back to honesty.</p>

    <p>If you're not honest, I genuinely believe it'll come back to hurt you eventually.</p>

    <p>I like to think of it like a wall.</p>

    <p>Every lie creates another crack in that wall.</p>

    <p>The more cracks you have, the more opportunities there are for everything to fall apart.</p>

    <p>Personally, I'd rather just be honest.</p>

    <p>That way, I don't have to worry about accidentally letting a secret slip or remembering what I told different people.</p>

    <p>Honestly, that's such an exhausting thing to worry about.</p>

    <p>I'd rather live carefree without constantly worrying about maintaining lies.</p>

    <p>That's another reason honesty and communication go hand in hand for me.</p>

    <p>Looking back on my own experiences, the situations where I've communicated honestly have almost always ended better than the situations where I tried to hide something or lie.</p>

    <p>From everything I've experienced, honesty is almost always the better choice.</p>

    <p>So that's something I strongly believe in.</p>

    <p>I don't really know what else to add.</p>

    <p>Once again, if there's something here that you disagree with or just want to talk about more, please let me know. Leave a comment, or even better, let's have an in-depth conversation in real life.</p>

    <p>I'd love that.</p>

    <p>Anyway, I have to meet with my research professor tomorrow morning for our one-hour stand-up meeting, and it's about a half-hour drive away.</p>

    <p>So I'm finally going to get some sleep.</p>

    <p>Anyway, that's about it.</p>

    <p>See you.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
