<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>On Friendship</title>
  <date>2026-06-29</date>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="video-embed">
      <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ou34GjrCWqc" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </div>

    <p>Going from the previous video, I literally talked about friendships and how friendships have been a very big part of my life. Like I said, getting out of my comfort zone really helped change things. But I want to talk about my definition of friendship because I struggled with that for a while too.</p>

    <p>Making friends was one thing, but I still struggled with questions like, "Would they consider me a friend? I consider them my friend, but is it really mutual? Or is it just me, and they actually have other friends?"</p>

    <p>I also had a very big insecurity back then. I literally had an anxious attachment style. I was clingy, especially with people I considered my best friends. I was always wondering, "Would they consider me their best friend too?" I constantly worried about whether the friendship was truly two-way.</p>

    <p>So I never really knew how to define friendship or what made someone a close friend until literally this year. I had always thought about it, but it wasn't until this year when I took another philosophy course. First, I took Philosophy of Happiness, and then the following quarter I took Philosophy of Friendship, both taught by the same professor. Good old professor. There was basically no homework or anything, but I learned a lot.</p>

    <p>The one thing that really stuck with me, after refining my own definition over and over again, was Aristotle's categories of friendship.</p>

    <p>There's the friendship of... I forgot the exact word, but it's basically acquaintances. These are people I know from work or other places.</p>

    <p>Then there's friendship of pleasure. These are friends that I can be myself around—well, at least in terms of my humor and personality. I'll still keep a lot of things about myself private, but I can joke around and act naturally.</p>

    <p>Even with acquaintances, I still believe I'm being myself, just a much more distant version of myself. I'm not showing my full personality.</p>

    <p>With friends of pleasure, I'm close enough to be my full goofy self. I'll make jokes that I wouldn't make around people I'm not close with. I don't have social anxiety around them. I'm not afraid to just have fun and joke around.</p>

    <p>But even then, I'll still be very secretive.</p>

    <p>So if you're someone I consider a friend of pleasure, you'll probably think I'm just this goofy person. I wouldn't really disclose much about myself unless you happened to watch this video, which is completely fine.</p>

    <p>It's only with friendships of virtue that things become different.</p>

    <p>Those are the people I've probably talked to about a lot of this stuff. Even then, I still don't open up all that much, but those friendships are what I consider my close friends.</p>

    <p>For the most part, I've learned that it really comes down to vibes.</p>

    <p>A close friend isn't just someone where the friendship is reciprocal. It's also someone whose character I genuinely respect. We don't have to believe in all the same things, but I admire the kind of person they are. In some ways, I almost look up to them.</p>

    <p>Honestly, it's probably true that everyone I consider a close friend has had some impact on my personality or my life.</p>

    <p>It's kind of embarrassing, but I actually keep a secret list of the people I consider close friends. It's not many people—only a handful.</p>

    <p>Honestly, I don't tell them enough how much of an impact they've had on me, but they really have.</p>

    <p>That's basically my definition of friendship and how I eventually arrived at it.</p>

    <p>At first, especially in high school, I was just focused on making friends. Like I said in my "getting out of my comfort zone" video, I basically had no friends.</p>

    <p>So my mindset was simply, "I just need friends. I just need people." I'd meet anyone.</p>

    <p>I still cared about having close friends, and I'd always hoped for that, but at the time I was mostly focused on just making friends in general.</p>

    <p>Then, during my senior year, I found out that a whole group of friends had been talking behind my back. I only found out because another guy told me—he knew because he was dating someone connected to that friend group.</p>

    <p>At the time, I didn't really know how to react. I just remember thinking, "I thought these guys were close." I had been hanging out with them almost every day, yet they were talking behind my back.</p>

    <p>One of them—even my ex at one point—almost got me suspended over a joke.</p>

    <p>Maybe I did take the joke too far, but that experience is one of the reasons I started creating a distinction between acquaintances and friends of pleasure.</p>

    <p>That was really the beginning of it.</p>

    <p>I gradually stopped talking to most people. My Instagram Close Friends list used to have way too many people on it, and then one day I cut it down to around ten almost instantly.</p>

    <p>I started asking myself, "Who are the real ones?"</p>

    <p>That question affected me a lot.</p>

    <p>For a while, I only had two categories: acquaintances and friends.</p>

    <p>I still didn't know how to define close friends.</p>

    <p>So there were just the people I could truly be myself around, and then there were the people I wasn't really close to and didn't fully trust.</p>

    <p>Trust is another thing I'll probably talk about in the next video I'm recording right after this. It actually bridges perfectly into that topic.</p>

    <p>Anyway, that's how I ended up with those two categories.</p>

    <p>Now, as for how I eventually came to define close friends...</p>

    <p>Taking the class was one part of it, but I also started realizing something through my own experiences.</p>

    <p>I don't remember the exact moment, but there was some drama involving people I considered friends of pleasure. I think it involved a girl as well.</p>

    <p>That whole situation made me realize something.</p>

    <p>These people were definitely friends of pleasure. I could be my goofy self around them, but they weren't people I truly respected. I didn't agree with a lot of the things they were doing. As much as I cared about them, they also didn't really disclose much about themselves.</p>

    <p>That's a key difference.</p>

    <p>The people I consider friends of virtue actually open up to me, and I open up to them too.</p>

    <p>With those other friends, I never felt like that level of openness was reciprocated. They were very secretive about who they actually were. They could tolerate me being my full goofy self, but we could never really connect on a deeper level.</p>

    <p>That's what separates a friend of virtue.</p>

    <p>The drama also made me realize that someone I had considered a close friend wasn't actually a close friend anymore. I tried helping them, but it didn't work out, and eventually I realized we just weren't meant to stay close. We simply weren't on the same path anymore.</p>

    <p>Of course, caring about someone is still part of it.</p>

    <p>For the most part, anyone in the "friends of pleasure" category or above is someone I genuinely care about. They're people I want to check in on.</p>

    <p>But friends of virtue... those are my ride-or-dies.</p>

    <p>I'm still a very secretive person. I think I've dropped a few hints throughout these videos about who those people are, so they'll probably know if they're watching.</p>

    <p>But generally, I'm very private about who I actually place in that category.</p>

    <p>Anyway, that's basically my definition of friendship.</p>

    <p>Friendship has honestly been one of the most important topics in my life.</p>

    <p>I even took AP Psychology because I wanted to learn about social psychology and how to make friends.</p>

    <p>I've also taken a total of five communication classes. I'm not kidding.</p>

    <p>When I started college classes in high school, most people began in the fall of their junior year. I decided to start during the summer because I wanted to get ahead, specifically to learn how to communicate better and make friends.</p>

    <p>I took two communication classes at first, and then I ended up taking three more—to the point where I was almost able to get a Communications minor.</p>

    <p>I never ended up doing that, though.</p>

    <p>Now I'm pursuing a double degree in Computer Science and Philosophy instead, and honestly, I'm much happier with that decision.</p>

    <p>But the reason I originally took all those communication classes was simply because I wanted to make friends.</p>

    <p>I've also taken two psychology classes.</p>

    <p>Then that interest naturally continued into philosophy, especially Philosophy of Friendship and Philosophy of Happiness. Those two classes really went hand in hand.</p>

    <p>Friendship was honestly the one thing that bothered me for most of my childhood.</p>

    <p>And I really was that privileged.</p>

    <p>I know other kids went through things that were so much worse, and I feel incredibly grateful for that. That's one of the reasons I always come back to talking about gratitude.</p>

    <p>At this point, though, I feel pretty settled with my definition of friendship.</p>

    <p>There are a few people I can confidently say belong in that close-friend category. They're people I trust completely. I don't have to worry about where I stand with them.</p>

    <p>And now, I think the next video is going to be about trust.</p>

    <p>So yeah, see you there.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
