<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>On Happiness</title>
  <date>2026-06-29</date>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="video-embed">
      <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/msfoMgwx3jU" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </div>

    <p>The definition of happiness, to me, is the ability to deal with things positively. I'm a pretty optimistic person, and I don't let problems get in the way of my overall outlook on life. For the most part, I stay positive no matter what happens. Even when bad things happen, I'm still grateful for where I am. Gratitude is one of my biggest values.</p>

    <p>I've spent a long time thinking about what happiness means. I even took an entire philosophy class on happiness. From that, I realized something that matched how I've already been living: I genuinely am a pretty happy person. My definition of happiness is being able to deal with suffering positively. I also believe happiness means living in the moment, being grateful, and making a positive impact on others. That's why I always try to be as altruistic as I can.</p>

    <p>For a long time, I've had two definitions of happiness. The first, which I've lived by since around COVID in middle school, is that happiness is living in the moment. One of the biggest pillars of my life is living in the moment. That doesn't mean ignoring the future or never thinking about the past. It just means fully appreciating what's happening right now while still planning responsibly.</p>

    <p>That mindset really started when I watched a lot of PewDiePie. Surprisingly, he introduced me to a lot of philosophy. The two philosophies that influenced me the most were Stoicism and Cynicism.</p>

    <p>Cynicism is obviously the extreme, and I don't actually follow it. It comes from Diogenes, who famously lived in a barrel and owned almost nothing. At one point, all he had was a bowl. Then he saw a child drinking water with their hands and realized he didn't even need that, so he gave the bowl away.</p>

    <p>One story that always stuck with me is that Alexander the Great supposedly said that if he weren't Alexander the Great, he would want to be Diogenes. To me, that shows that wealth and possessions aren't everything. Diogenes took living in the present to the absolute extreme. He genuinely didn't care what people thought of him. The guy was wild.</p>

    <p>Obviously, I'm not saying we should only think about the present. It's important to plan for the future too. But I really connected with another idea PewDiePie talked about. He reacted to the death of a Bollywood actor whose message about happiness centered on living in the moment. He used the example that, as a kid during recess, you weren't thinking about the past or the future. You were just completely immersed in playing.</p>

    <p>That idea really resonated with me because I think living in the moment brings me the most joy.</p>

    <p>Take concerts, for example. Most people pull out their phones and record the whole thing. There's nothing wrong with recording—I do it too—but when I record, my videos are shaky because I'm dancing, singing, and actually enjoying the experience. Some people spend the entire concert trying to get the perfect angle. Personally, I don't understand how that's more enjoyable than simply being there and experiencing it.</p>

    <p>Living in the moment has become a huge part of who I am.</p>

    <p>I also recognize that I'm in a privileged position to even have this outlook. I'm grateful that I've been able to stay content with life. I wouldn't be surprised if there are experiences out there that could completely change my perspective, and I'm thankful I've never had to go through something like that.</p>

    <p>Of course, I still get sad. Happiness isn't the same thing as the emotion of being happy. A happy life includes experiencing sadness, frustration, grief, and every other emotion. Expecting to feel happy all the time is unrealistic. That's never been my definition.</p>

    <p>Life gets really hard sometimes. That's just part of being alive. But even through those setbacks, I believe my overall outlook will stay the same. I'll still be content with life.</p>

    <p>So my two definitions of happiness are:</p>

    <ol>
      <li>Being able to deal with suffering positively.</li>
      <li>Living in the moment.</li>
    </ol>

    <p>I'd also add gratitude to that definition because I honestly think gratitude is one of the foundations of happiness. I'm happy because I'm grateful for what I have. If I wasn't grateful, I don't think I'd be nearly as happy.</p>

    <p>From what I've observed, people who aren't grateful are never satisfied. They're always chasing something else. They take what they already have for granted and keep wanting more. To me, happiness requires some level of satisfaction with your life. Gratitude allows you to appreciate what you already have instead of constantly focusing on what's missing.</p>

    <p>Everything I believe comes from my experiences—my family, my friends, and everyone who's been part of my life.</p>

    <p>If any of you are listening to this, thank you. I'm grateful for everything you've done for me, and I'll always try to be there for you.</p>

    <p>I say that because there was a point in my life where I felt like I had almost no real friends. Sure, I'd play with random kids during recess, but I never felt like I had close connections with anyone. At home, I mostly kept to myself. Even at school, I rarely talked to people. I stayed quiet and just tried to get through the day.</p>

    <p>That honestly sucked.</p>

    <p>As privileged as it sounds, loneliness was probably the biggest struggle I faced growing up.</p>

    <p>After quarantine, I made a conscious effort to change my life by stepping outside my comfort zone. Ever since then, things have been a lot better. That's another value I hold very strongly: getting out of my comfort zone. Almost every time I've pushed myself to do something uncomfortable, I've been rewarded for it.</p>

    <p>That's probably a topic for another video.</p>

    <p>But that's my view on happiness.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
