<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>On The Meaning Of Life</title>
  <date>2026-06-29</date>
  <summary>Anh-Thien Nguyen</summary>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="video-embed">
      <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rnELh4-q3Ww" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </div>

    <p>I'm here to talk about the meaning of life.</p>

    <p>I briefly mentioned it in my happiness video, but I wasn't very specific.</p>

    <p>Another thing to know about me is that I highly value definitions. Even though I don't always explain things very precisely in conversation, I care a lot about having clear definitions and being specific. That probably comes from taking classes in deductive and inductive logic. I really enjoy that kind of thinking, so I naturally value precise definitions.</p>

    <p>Because of that, I wanted to make a separate video about the meaning of life. I touched on it before, but I don't think I explained it well enough. I was also really tired while recording those videos, so I kept using the word "happiness" to substitute for a lot of different ideas.</p>

    <p>So here's my actual answer.</p>

    <p>My meaning of life is simply to enjoy life.</p>

    <p>That ties directly into my belief in living in the moment.</p>

    <p>This idea mostly developed through taking philosophy classes. The topic of the meaning of life came up a lot, especially in my Philosophy of Happiness course.</p>

    <p>For the longest time, I considered myself an optimistic nihilist.</p>

    <p>That idea originally came from a Kurzgesagt video that YouTube randomly recommended to me.</p>

    <p>Not just a nihilist, but an <strong>optimistic</strong> nihilist.</p>

    <p>The idea was that life doesn't necessarily have some predetermined cosmic meaning, and that's okay. I didn't think I had a specific purpose. I just wanted to enjoy life.</p>

    <p>One day, I was talking with someone I consider a friend of virtue—a very close friend whom I highly respect. We don't always agree on everything, but I respect him a lot.</p>

    <p>He believes that everyone has a meaning in life.</p>

    <p>He believes everyone is searching for meaning.</p>

    <p>I disagreed.</p>

    <p>I said, "I don't think I have one."</p>

    <p>That fit with the way I understood nihilism.</p>

    <p>Later, I had a completely separate conversation with another close friend after a rave.</p>

    <p>The topic somehow came up again.</p>

    <p>I mentioned what my other friend had said—that everyone has a meaning in life.</p>

    <p>Again, I said I didn't think I had one.</p>

    <p>I explained that I honestly didn't care about having some grand purpose.</p>

    <p>I just wanted to enjoy life.</p>

    <p>A lot of the things I do are simply because I think they're fun.</p>

    <p>I'll admit that way of thinking was also influenced by another friend I really respect.</p>

    <p>I genuinely do a lot of things simply because I enjoy doing them.</p>

    <p>If I don't enjoy the journey, I probably wouldn't do it.</p>

    <p>For example, I genuinely enjoy school.</p>

    <p>I enjoy learning computer science just as much as I enjoy learning philosophy.</p>

    <p>That's one of the reasons I'm pursuing a Philosophy major.</p>

    <p>It's simply fun.</p>

    <p>So my mindset was always, "I don't really have a purpose. I just want to enjoy life."</p>

    <p>Then that friend asked me one question that completely changed how I thought about it.</p>

    <p>He said,</p>

    <blockquote>"Isn't your purpose just enjoying life?"</blockquote>

    <p>That completely shifted my perspective.</p>

    <p>I realized that maybe I <em>do</em> have a meaning in life.</p>

    <p>It's simply to enjoy life.</p>

    <p>To live in the moment.</p>

    <p>To be grateful.</p>

    <p>And to make a positive impact on other people.</p>

    <p>Gratitude is still a huge part of that.</p>

    <p>Without gratitude, I don't think I'd actually enjoy anything.</p>

    <p>If I wasn't grateful for what I already have, I'd constantly be focused on what I don't have instead.</p>

    <p>For me, gratitude is what allows me to truly appreciate life.</p>

    <p>When I think about it, almost everything I do is because I enjoy doing it.</p>

    <p>Sometimes people ask, "If your purpose is just to enjoy life and live in the moment, then why do you still pursue goals? Doesn't that contradict what you're saying?"</p>

    <p>Maybe it does.</p>

    <p>That's something I'm still open to refining, and I'd love to have more discussions about it.</p>

    <p>But personally, I think life would be pretty boring without goals.</p>

    <p>Goals make life fun.</p>

    <p>I enjoy school, but it would be kind of boring to just take random classes forever.</p>

    <p>I want to work toward earning a degree.</p>

    <p>Obviously, I also can't completely ignore money.</p>

    <p>Money is important.</p>

    <p>Part of the reason I chose Computer Science is because it provides financial stability.</p>

    <p>But something like Philosophy?</p>

    <p>That's honestly just for fun.</p>

    <p>I'm also incredibly fortunate that my education is essentially free.</p>

    <p>If it weren't for that, my decisions might look very different.</p>

    <p>I'm very grateful to be in the position I'm in.</p>

    <p>This ended up being an even shorter video than the others.</p>

    <p>I just wanted to make sure I talked about the meaning of life somewhere because it's something that's important to me.</p>

    <p>Again, if you disagree with anything I've said—or if you just want to discuss it more—please leave a comment or talk to me in real life.</p>

    <p>I'd genuinely love to hear your thoughts.</p>

    <p>Anyway, that's about it.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
