<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>The Myth of Social Hierarchies</title>
  <date>2026-07-23</date>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="audio-embed">
      <audio controls src="posts/audio/on-friend-groups.m4a"></audio>
    </div>

    <p>Just a random thought, but I think so-called social hierarchies in friend groups mostly come from people who simply put in more effort than others.</p>

    <p>For example, I have a friend group where there's one person who's incredibly friendly toward everyone. Everyone feels close to them. I don't think that's because they're "popular" or because they're playing some sort of power game. I think it's simply because they genuinely put in the effort to build relationships with everyone.</p>

    <p>Friend groups aren't naturally equal. You're never going to be equally close with every single person. Some people will naturally be closer to you than others.</p>

    <p>But if you intentionally put in the effort to get to know everyone—to become close enough that each person considers you a close friend—you naturally become one of the core people in the group.</p>

    <p>You don't even have to be equally close with everyone. You just have to build meaningful relationships with enough people.</p>

    <p>Eventually, you become one of the people who ties the group together.</p>

    <p>If you leave, conversations might feel awkward because you're the bridge between multiple people.</p>

    <p>That made me realize something.</p>

    <p>When someone worries, "I'm always ignored in this friend group,"—which, I'll admit, I used to do when I was younger—it might simply be because they haven't put enough effort into getting to know everyone individually.</p>

    <p>Of course, there's another possibility.</p>

    <p>Maybe you <em>did</em> put in the effort, and it just didn't work out.</p>

    <p>In that case, maybe the group just isn't for you.</p>

    <p>I've been in quite a few friend groups throughout my life, and I've realized that it depends heavily on the people.</p>

    <p>You can't force yourself into becoming the "center" of every social group because sometimes you simply don't fit.</p>

    <p>I think it's similar to cooking.</p>

    <p>Imagine you're really confident in your ability to cook a steak. You make one for someone, and they don't like it.</p>

    <p>You have two ways to react.</p>

    <p>The first is to think,</p>

    <blockquote><em>"Oh my God, they didn't like my steak. My self-esteem is ruined. What am I doing wrong?"</em></blockquote>

    <p>The second is,</p>

    <blockquote><em>"I know my steak is good. I like how I make it. They just don't like it, and that's okay. It's a matter of preference."</em></blockquote>

    <p>That's self-esteem.</p>

    <p>You know your own value, so you don't let one person's opinion completely define you.</p>

    <p>I think friend groups work the same way.</p>

    <p>Sometimes you don't need to change yourself just to fit in.</p>

    <p>Sometimes the group simply isn't your crowd.</p>

    <p>I actually got really lucky.</p>

    <p>My childhood friend group never really felt like my people.</p>

    <p>I don't think it was anyone's fault.</p>

    <p>They weren't bad people.</p>

    <p>I just don't think we were the right fit for each other.</p>

    <p>When I was younger, though, I didn't realize that. I just thought, "These are the people I'm always around, so this must be where I belong."</p>

    <p>Because of that, I constantly felt like I was at the bottom of the social hierarchy.</p>

    <p>Then I moved to a different school.</p>

    <p>Almost immediately, I found people I clicked with.</p>

    <p>Those feelings mostly disappeared.</p>

    <p>That experience taught me that sometimes it isn't about becoming more likable.</p>

    <p>Sometimes it's simply about finding the right people.</p>

    <p>This whole thought actually came after watching one of Jeff's videos about friend groups.</p>

    <p>It made me realize that the people who become the center of a group usually do one of three things.</p>

    <p>Either they naturally connect with everyone because they're very charismatic...</p>

    <p>They intentionally put in the effort to become close with everyone...</p>

    <p>Or they realize a particular group isn't for them and find one where they fit better.</p>

    <p>Personally, I'm not charismatic enough to instantly become friends with everyone.</p>

    <p>I know people who can walk into a room and naturally connect with almost anybody.</p>

    <p>That's not me.</p>

    <p>If I don't consciously put effort into socializing, I'll usually just feed off everyone else's energy instead of leading conversations.</p>

    <p>But when I <em>do</em> want to become more involved in a group, I've found that the best thing to do is simply spend time getting to know everyone individually.</p>

    <p>I actually did this once.</p>

    <p>For my graduation party, I invited a bunch of friends who didn't know each other.</p>

    <p>Over time, they all became friends.</p>

    <p>Since everyone originally knew me before they knew each other, I naturally became one of the central people in that group.</p>

    <p>Interestingly, though, that didn't last forever.</p>

    <p>Shortly afterward, another friend became the one who hosted the most hangouts.</p>

    <p>They were constantly reaching out to people and planning things.</p>

    <p>Naturally, they became one of the core people in the group.</p>

    <p>I saw the same thing happen in one of my university friend groups.</p>

    <p>The group was really active for a while, but then some drama happened and everything slowly died down.</p>

    <p>One friend, though, kept putting in the effort.</p>

    <p>He suggested we go around rating pizza places.</p>

    <p>Then that turned into regular hangouts.</p>

    <p>Because he kept reaching out and organizing things, he naturally became one of the central people in the group.</p>

    <p>It wasn't because everyone thought he was "popular."</p>

    <p>I honestly think that idea of popularity is a very elementary-school way of looking at friendships.</p>

    <p>The people we often think of as "popular" are usually just the people who are willing to put in the effort.</p>

    <p>They're either naturally charismatic and can connect with almost anyone...</p>

    <p>Or they're the ones constantly reaching out, planning hangouts, and maintaining friendships.</p>

    <p>So if you're struggling to fit into a friend group, I think there are two questions worth asking yourself.</p>

    <p>First, have you actually put in the effort to get to know everyone individually and help maintain the group?</p>

    <p>And second, if you have, is this group simply not the right fit for you?</p>

    <p>Sometimes the answer is the first.</p>

    <p>Sometimes it's the second.</p>

    <p>And that's okay.</p>

    <p>Anyway, those are just my thoughts.</p>

    <p>See you.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
