<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Trust, Honesty, Accountability, and Forgiveness</title>
  <date>2026-06-29</date>
  <summary>Anh-Thien Nguyen</summary>
  <body><![CDATA[
    <div class="video-embed">
      <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QOfF0MM4Xjk" title="YouTube video player" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
    </div>

    <p>Yeah, I'm recording this right after the previous video, the friendship one, and now I want to talk about trust because it's very intertwined with friendship.</p>

    <p>At one point, trust was probably the value I cared about the most. I still highly value trust. My trust in people hasn't been as strong lately, but trust is still one of the biggest pillars of my life. I always try to trust people first because I believe it's led to the best outcomes overall.</p>

    <p>Interestingly, this idea also came from YouTube.</p>

    <p>Most of my philosophy interests came from PewDiePie, but my views on trust actually came from <strong>The Game Theorists</strong>. The host was Matthew Patrick, better known as <strong>MatPat</strong>. I think he's pretty well known. At least, I feel like most of my friends know who he is.</p>

    <p>His final video before stepping down as host talked about four key values. He demonstrated them through the Prisoner's Dilemma, and while that's only one way to test the idea, it really resonated with me.</p>

    <p>I'm actually doing summer research right now on a different simulated society to see whether this same framework holds up in a broader setting.</p>

    <p>The framework is simple:</p>

    <ul>
      <li>Trust.</li>
      <li>Be honest.</li>
      <li>Hold people accountable.</li>
      <li>Be willing to forgive.</li>
    </ul>

    <p>I highly value honesty, so I always try to trust people and communicate honestly.</p>

    <p>Then comes accountability. If someone betrays your trust, you have to hold them accountable. Accountability is something I value a lot as well.</p>

    <p>Finally, you have to be willing to forgive.</p>

    <p>This framework comes from the Prisoner's Dilemma, where two agents repeatedly choose whether to cooperate or betray each other.</p>

    <p>If you betray someone, you might get a bigger reward in that single round. But over time, the strategy called <strong>Tit for Tat</strong> consistently performs the best.</p>

    <p>Tit for Tat always starts by cooperating. It trusts the other agent first.</p>

    <p>If the other agent betrays it, Tit for Tat betrays them in the next round.</p>

    <p>But if the other agent goes back to cooperating, Tit for Tat immediately cooperates again.</p>

    <p>That's basically the framework I try to follow.</p>

    <p>Trust people first. Cooperate first. But if someone betrays that trust, hold them accountable. Then, if they genuinely change, be willing to forgive and trust again.</p>

    <p>There were many different strategies tested in the Prisoner's Dilemma, and Tit for Tat consistently came out near the top. The strategies that constantly betrayed everyone usually ended up with the fewest points because, over time, nobody wanted to cooperate with them anymore.</p>

    <p>From my own experience, I genuinely believe this is one of the best ways to approach life.</p>

    <p>Being able to trust people and communicate honestly has almost always led to the most rewarding relationships.</p>

    <p>Communication itself is probably the next topic I'll talk about because that's a whole subject on its own.</p>

    <p>Being honest in communication is incredibly important.</p>

    <p>Holding people accountable is something I'll admit I'm still not very good at. I'm still too much of a people pleaser. I struggle to communicate when someone has crossed a line.</p>

    <p>But I'm working on it.</p>

    <p>Ironically, many of the people I consider friends of virtue are very direct people. They're willing to hold others accountable.</p>

    <p>That's one of the reasons I respect them so much.</p>

    <p>In a way, we complement each other. I'm too much of a people pleaser, while they're very direct.</p>

    <p>Sometimes they'll even say being so direct is one of their weaknesses, but I always tell them I think it's a strength.</p>

    <p>I highly value honesty and accountability, and because they're willing to be direct, they naturally embody both of those values.</p>

    <p>Like I mentioned in my friendship video, I'm such a people pleaser because I grew up feeling like I had no friends.</p>

    <p>Because of that, I'm afraid of losing people.</p>

    <p>A lot of this really stems from that experience.</p>

    <p>The last value is forgiveness.</p>

    <p>Honestly, it's exhausting to keep hating someone forever.</p>

    <p>Why keep carrying that around?</p>

    <p>If someone genuinely changes, then they change.</p>

    <p>Just let it go.</p>

    <p>Just chill.</p>

    <p>This is surprisingly a much shorter video.</p>

    <p>I don't really know what else to add besides saying that I value these four principles together as a complete framework:</p>

    <ul>
      <li>Trust.</li>
      <li>Honesty.</li>
      <li>Accountability.</li>
      <li>Forgiveness.</li>
    </ul>

    <p>If you're interested, I'd highly recommend watching MatPat's farewell video from The Game Theorists.</p>

    <p>I'd also recommend Veritasium's video on the Prisoner's Dilemma. It does a great job explaining why strategies like Tit for Tat work so well.</p>

    <p>Right now, I'm also doing research with a professor on social contract theory, which aligns really closely with this framework.</p>

    <p>It's still the beginning of the summer, so I haven't gotten very far yet, but I'm hoping to test whether this same framework also works in an artificial society—not just in the Prisoner's Dilemma.</p>

    <p>Anyway, communication will probably be the next video.</p>

    <p>So, yeah. See you then.</p>
  ]]></body>
</post>
